<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food4Thought</title>
    <link>/Food4Thought/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Food4Thought</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/Food4Thought/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning and Reinforcement Learning (DLRL) Summer School 2020</title>
      <link>/Food4Thought/2020/dlrl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Food4Thought/2020/dlrl/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning and Reinforcement Learning (DLRL) Summer School 2020 This year, I was 1 of the 300 participants selected from around the globe for the DLRL 2020.
This is a prestigious annual event organized by the 3 major machine learning reaseach institutes in Canada: MILA (Montreal), Vector (Toronto) and Amii (Alberta), all brought together through CIFAR.
Overall impression I was impressed by the number of women on the lecture panel and the number of women attending the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dividing lines: discritizing contineous scales for our ease</title>
      <link>/Food4Thought/2020/dividinglines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Food4Thought/2020/dividinglines/</guid>
      <description>Dividing lines: discretizing contineous scales for our ease Dividing lines in University: Throughout my education, I tried to have a large scope of anything I do. The &amp;ldquo;Big Picture&amp;rdquo; matters to me and I usually define broad lines; the What?, the Why?, and the How? are always scrutinized ahead of every task. I have also always believed in grey zones and multi-disciplinarity. My undergraduate degree was in Biochemitrsy, a field that is at the borderline between Biology and Chemistry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Field of Study: Chromatin Architecture</title>
      <link>/Food4Thought/2020/hic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Food4Thought/2020/hic/</guid>
      <description>My Field of Study: Chromatin Architecture My research career has involved multiple different fields and countless questions. My area of expertise though is that which I worked on for the larger part of my PhD: Genomics. Specifically, my PhD thesis examined genetic aspects of the development of an aggressive brain cancer, Glioblastoma. Much of my PhD work remains to be published. It involves looking at DNA folding or chromatin architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Science, Med. School &amp; Engineering</title>
      <link>/Food4Thought/2020/researcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Food4Thought/2020/researcher/</guid>
      <description>Research Science, Med School &amp;amp; Engineering I was always fascinated with Science. The Why and How intrigue me. As a child, I would sit and watch toy mechanisms to draw out how they function and would disassemble broken toys before discarding them to see what they contained. The research scientists with their white lab coats and pipettes were an image I often romanticized.
I knew at a very early age that I&amp;rsquo;d be a researcher, to the disappointment of my parents who like most other arab parents, prefered professions like Medicine or Engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing Server Welcome Message</title>
      <link>/Food4Thought/2020/linux_motd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Food4Thought/2020/linux_motd/</guid>
      <description>Customizing Server Welcome Message I recently set up a home server as a small project to keep me sane during the COVID-19 social distancing period. I have been slowly customizing it to my liking to have a fully functional server that I can host files on and to learn a thing or two about Linux Sys Admin tasks.
I wanted to customize the text that gets printed out when you first log into a server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing your Prompt</title>
      <link>/Food4Thought/2020/linux_prompt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Food4Thought/2020/linux_prompt/</guid>
      <description>Customizing Your Prompt I recently set up a home server as a small project to keep me sane during the COVID-19 social distancing period. I have been slowly customizing it to my liking to have a fully functional server that I can host files on and to learn a thing or two about Linux Sys Admin tasks.
One of the first things I do on any new server is to customize my prompt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self Notes from my PhD</title>
      <link>/Food4Thought/2020/phd_tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Food4Thought/2020/phd_tips/</guid>
      <description>Self Notes from my PhD I have been in academic research for over 10 years. I started as a lab intern in the summer of 2007 on an NSERC USRA scholarhsip and have been in research ever since. I have worked in various fields including bacterial and fungal evolution, heart development, mouse work, plant and fungal symbiosis, brain development, cancer, stem cells and chromatin architecture, to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up a CentOS7 home server</title>
      <link>/Food4Thought/2020/server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Food4Thought/2020/server/</guid>
      <description>Setting Up a CentOS 7 home server 
I have been planning to set up a home server for a year now but have been putting it off. This week, with the COVID-19 lockdown, my husband and I pulled out the 3 ancient computers sitting in our garage to set up one decent home server. The purpose was mainly curiosity; to play with pieces of hardware and software to learn a few things and to have our own little server to test various pipelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19: sense in a time of non-sense</title>
      <link>/Food4Thought/2020/covid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Food4Thought/2020/covid19/</guid>
      <description>COVID-19: sense in a time of non-sense 
As I watch people around me panic, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d scribble down the words that I have been reciting to my husband three times a day for the last week. He is an emotional person, like many, and has found it hard to keep a focused, rational thinking process about the situation despite his PhD in Systems Biology, 2 Masters and 2 undergrads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up GenPipes on Compute Canada Servers</title>
      <link>/Food4Thought/2018/genpipes_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Food4Thought/2018/genpipes_setup/</guid>
      <description>Objective In this practical, we will set up GenPipes, to be able to access its installed modules, pipelines and genomes.

Setting up GenPipes To set up GenPipes, you will need to add some lines of code in your bash_profile file on the server you will be using. The bash_profile is a hidden file in your home directory that sets up your environment every time you log in. Alternatively, you can also use your bashrc file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Rola Dali&#39;s Blog</title>
      <link>/Food4Thought/2018/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Food4Thought/2018/hello-world/</guid>
      <description> Hello World!  “Yeah It&amp;rsquo;s alive!. ”
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/Food4Thought/post/mcgill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Food4Thought/post/mcgill/</guid>
      <description>subtitle: &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; description: &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; date: 2020-09-25 author: &amp;ldquo;Rola Dali&amp;rdquo; URL: &amp;ldquo;/2020/mcgill/index.html&amp;rdquo; tags: - tribute - McGill
categories: [ Opinion ]
image: &amp;ldquo;&amp;rdquo; Made By McGill Today marks my last day at McGill University&amp;hellip;
2020 denotes my 10th year at McGill; in January 2011, I stepped onto the McGill campus as a young, naive PhD candidate. Today, as I prepare for a new adventure, I will inevitably miss McGill and everyone here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/Food4Thought/search/placeholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Food4Thought/search/placeholder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>